<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[New York Intellectual Property Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/73171</id>
  <updated>2017-07-19T15:21:06Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This New York, New York blog by W. R. Samuels Law PLLC discusses legal issues related to Intellectual Property. We hope you'll provide your feedback.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What's in a Name?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/07/whats-in-a-name.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2679281</id>
  <published>2017-07-17T18:08:00Z</published>
  <updated>2017-07-19T15:21:06Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[It's one of those things that you know, but it's rarely front of mind. You never think about it, but you're bombarded by it daily. A NAME embodies a whole effort. When you reference your efforts in business--whether for...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Bill Samuels]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Trademarks" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="business" label="Business" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="investment" label="Investment" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="name" label="Name" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="trademarkliability" label="Trademark Liability" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/#sthash.dmrpO31g.CVfd0l9R.dpbs"><img alt="Thumbnail image for Thumbnail image for what's in a name DPLIC 40832005.jpg" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/07/what's in a name DPLIC 40832005-thumb-500x375-89146-thumb-500x375-89147-thumb-500x375-89148.jpg" width="500" height="375" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></a></p> <p>It's one of those things that you know, but it's rarely front of mind. You never think about it, but you're bombarded by it daily. A NAME embodies a whole effort.</p> <p>When you reference your efforts in business<span style="font-family: Helvetica; font-size: 12px;">--</span>whether for profit or non-profit<span style="font-family: Helvetica; font-size: 12px;">--</span>at a certain time you use a name, or a symbol, or a sound or something else to identify those efforts (i.e., a "NAME"). Unilever does. UNICEF does, too.</p> <p> <style type="text/css"><!-- p.p1 {margin: 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px; font: 12.0px Helvetica} --></style> </p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>You see, that NAME may tell people your professional association certifies a product, it may tell folks you made a product or you offer a service, or it may be a way for you to communicate to others what your values are. The NAME identifies the technology, function, design, lifestyle, and sociocultural substance of your effort and resulting goods and services. For better or worse.</p> <p>Simply using that NAME is a definite investment in that name. You want to have confidence in that NAME. That NAME is your trademark. Avoid conflicts.</p> <p>It can be hard to have a warehouse filled with widgets that you cannot sell because of trademark liability. Can you get the trademark off the product, and at what cost? Or maybe your App has been downloaded thousands of times under a certain NAME. Or you've invested thousands in your marketing plan, design, and e-commerce site. What do you do then? Or perhaps your NAME is particularly difficult and/or expensive to protect. Just a NAME can throw a wrench in the works of your efforts.</p> <p>Avoid investing in a NAME (or IP, generally) that you may need to change later. Save money on: product R&D; engineering; multimedia and social media campaigns; SEO; marketing and advertising; and design of all types (e.g., product, logo, retail location, restaurant, Web site, etc.).</p> <p>Understand and be deliberate in your NAME. In the interest of building value and goodwill in that NAME, consider your right to use the NAME or any possible issues that could come up if you use it. That NAME will embody and represent your work. (There's a reason they call it "branding.")</p> <p>If it doesn't matter to you, fine. Reach out when it comes up. If it does matter<span style="font-family: Helvetica; font-size: 12px;">--</span>and it does<span style="font-family: Helvetica; font-size: 12px;">--</span>consider your options and weigh them against resources, near-term plans, long-term plans, and your business objectives. It's all in a NAME.</p> <p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2016/11/bill samuels-thumb-150x112-78738.jpg"><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="112" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/01/bill samuels-thumb-150x112-78738-thumb-150x112-80935.jpg" alt="Thumbnail image for bill samuels.jpg" /></a></p> <p><em><strong>WILLIAM R. SAMUELS</strong></em><br /> <strong>212-206-9399 </strong><br /> <a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/E-mail.shtml?guid=U4dE1fa50BlHZO7CpK+RKv2bS+wwniDvqMMX70SrgTQ1WTpvJJRfjsWAEe6x96pwOqfuWSc8S5rQxXIN8peT2kI2Y05vNTcDuOYavnc2cwfTHRQOw0GZuqcVFaG0i9rlbA9YF2Eh4q5x+oehshS8ggtGHM70RUnMLzwV8MZrxs0=&attorneyName=William%20R.%20Samuels"><strong>Email me</strong></a>&nbsp;</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Transformative Use of Copyrighted Material Is Highly Subjective]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/06/transformative-use-of-copyrighted-material-is-highly-subjective.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2656111</id>
  <published>2017-06-28T14:54:18Z</published>
  <updated>2017-06-29T22:29:04Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[In our previous blog article, we explored the concept of fair use and how courts determine whether the use of copyrighted material is permitted without the rightsholder's permission under the Constitution's statute. One way to decide whether the fair...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Iva Rukelj]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Copyright" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="abbottandcostello" label="Abbott and Costello" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="copyrightedmaterial" label="Copyrighted Material" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="handtogod" label="Hand to God" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="intellectualproperty" label="Intellectual Property" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/Transformative%20Use%20of%20Copyrighted%20Material%20Is%20Highly%20Subjective%20dplic%20144710201.jpg"><img style="margin: 0px 0px 20px 20px;" class="mt-image-right" height="300" width="375" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/06/Transformative Use of Copyrighted Material Is Highly Subjective dplic 144710201-thumb-500x333-88508.jpg" alt="Transformative Use of Copyrighted Material Is Highly Subjective by Iva Rukelj" /></a></p> <p>In our previous <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/06/its-fair-to-say-fair-use-is-complicated.shtml#sthash.nDlxVUq8.dpbs">blog article</a>, we explored the concept of fair use and how courts determine whether the use of copyrighted material is permitted <em>without </em>the rightsholder's permission under the Constitution's statute.</p> <p>One way to decide whether the fair use law applies is to determine whether the third party engaged in the <strong>transformative use</strong> of the copyrighted material. New York's active Second Circuit Court recently ruled on two applicable cases, elucidating the intricacies of fair use.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Who's on First?</strong></p> <p>The Second Circuit decided a very interesting matter about the use of the classic "Who's on first?" routine by the legendary comedy duo Abbott and Costello. <em>TCA Television Corp. v. McCollum</em>, 839 F.3d 168 (2d Cir. 2016).</p> <p>This familiar routine revolved around the interplay of baseball players oddly named as Who, What, and I Don't Know. Abbott and Costello would go back and forth in an exasperated attempt to understand the situation, asking questions like "Who's on first," which was a statement and not a question-you get the idea.</p> <p><em>Hand to God</em> is a stage play that included the "Who's on first?" routine described above, but with a sock puppet telling it. The producers of the play saw the Abbott and Costello routine as something that was commonly known, and they also thought that the way that they used it-as a critique of the social norms governing a small town in the Bible Belt-would suffice and justify their use of the routine.</p> <p>And the District Court agreed with them. However, the Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit reversed that decision, holding that it was not transformative use because:</p> <ul> <li> <p>The play did not add any new elements, expressions, meaning or message to the classic bit.</p> </li> <li> <p>The retelling of the "Who's on first?" bit portrayed in <em>Hand to God</em> exhausted the entire routine.</p> </li> <li> <p><em>Hand to God</em>'s use of the routine was commercial in nature.</p> </li> <li> <p>The use did affect a derivative market for a license for the routine.</p> </li> <li> <p>"Who's on first?" has been largely licensed by others.</p> </li> </ul> <p>What is perhaps most interesting about this case-and further evidence of the wisdom in hiring counsel to protect your intellectual property-is that <em>Hand to God</em> still (sort of) won! In a later decision, the court found that Abbott and Costello's heirs had no legal standing to sue for infringement. It appears that after their initial 1944 copyright, Abbott and Costello <a target="_blank" href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/thr-esq/abbott-costello-heirs-lose-appeal-937178">never renewed it</a>.</p> <p>To learn more about how we can help you, <a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Contact.shtml#sthash.N5w2cOCF.dpbs">click here</a>.</p> <p><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="120" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/iva.jpg" alt="iva.jpg" /></p> <p><em><strong>IVA RUKELJ</strong><strong> </strong></em><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Attorneys/Iva-Rukelj.shtml"><br /> 212-206-9399 <br /> </a><a href="/E-mail.shtml">Email me</a></p> <p><span style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"></span></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[It's Fair to Say Fair Use Is Complicated]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/06/its-fair-to-say-fair-use-is-complicated.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2635656</id>
  <published>2017-06-11T18:40:39Z</published>
  <updated>2017-06-12T18:03:01Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[While the framers of the Constitution had no way of predicting the kinds of technology we enjoy today, they did have the foresight to understand the necessity of intellectual property rights. That is why the Constitution gives artists and...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Iva Rukelj]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Intellectual Property" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="artists" label="Artists" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="copyrightact" label="Copyright Act" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="fairuse" label="Fair Use" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="intellectualpropertyrights" label="Intellectual Property Rights" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="inventors" label="Inventors" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/06/its-fair-to-say-fair-use-is-complicated.shtml"><img alt="It's Fair to Say Fair Use Is Complicated by Iva Rukelj" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/06/It's Fair to Say Fair Use Is Complicated DPLIC 128445044-thumb-500x431-87724.jpg" width="500" height="400" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0px auto 20px;" /></a></p> <p>While the framers of the Constitution had no way of predicting the kinds of technology we enjoy today, they did have the foresight to understand the necessity of intellectual property rights. That is why the Constitution gives artists and inventors an exclusive right to their work under Article I, Section 8, Clause 8:</p> <p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-style: italic;">To promote the Progress of Science and useful Arts, by securing for limited Times to Authors and Inventors the exclusive Right to their respective Writings and Discoveries.</span></p> <p>Out of that Constitutional clause, American copyright law was born, and with it, a qualified exception to the same exclusive rights it guarantees called <span style="font-weight: bold;">fair use</span>.&nbsp;</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Fair use balances the exclusive rights granted to authors by the Constitution and the Copyright Act and gives others an opportunity to use works without infringing on someone's copyright. Some examples of <strong>fair use</strong> include:</p> <ul> <li> <p>Teaching</p> </li> <li> <p>Research</p> </li> <li> <p>Criticism</p> </li> <li> <p>News</p> </li> </ul> <p>When trying to determine if a work is <span style="font-style: italic;">not</span> fair use, there are additional elements that courts employ in order to make their determinations:</p> <ul> <li> <p>Character of the use</p> </li> <li> <p>Nature of the copyrighted work</p> </li> <li> <p>Amount and specialty of the use</p> </li> <li> <p>Second potential market</p> </li> </ul> <p>If a rightsholder decides to commence a lawsuit, all copyright disputes begin in Federal District Court. However, the Appellate Circuit Courts often have the final say, either reversing or upholding the District Courts. No two Circuit Courts are the same, but one of the most active is New York's Second Circuit.</p> <p>Many interesting developments emerge from the Second Circuit. This Court decided on two cases that examined <span style="font-style: italic;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">transformative use</span></span> of copyrighted material. Transformative use is an example where the type of <span style="font-style: italic;">character of use</span> element was determinative of whether something is fair use.</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">One Artist, Two Decisions</span></p> <p>Jeff Koons is a New York-based visual artist and sculptor who draws inspiration from the work of others. One such work involved transforming a photograph (of puppies!) into a 3D statue. The photographer, Art Rogers, saw what Koons had done with his photo and became indignant&nbsp;because he felt that Koons stole his theme and his work. In <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rogers_v._Koons"></a><a><span style="font-style: italic;">Rogers v. Ko</span></a><span style="font-style: italic;">o</span><a><span style="font-style: italic;">ns</span></a>, the court agreed with Rogers, stating that Koons's use, even though it was in a different medium, was not transformative enough to be a fair use. <span style="font-style: italic;">Rogers v. Koons</span>, 960 F.2d 301, 309 (2d Cir. 1992).</p> <p>Another example, this time in which Koons was victorious, can be found in <span style="font-style: italic;">Blanch v. Koons</span>. In this case, Koons put together a picture involving different clippings of feet. Even though Koons literally lifted one of these images from a Gucci spread in a magazine, the courts said that the <span style="font-style: italic;">way</span> in which he put it together, and used it in the larger piece, was so transformative it was considered as a fair use. <span style="font-style: italic;">Blanch v. Koons,</span> 467 F.3d 244, 253 (2d Cir. 2006).</p> <p>The takeaway is that the line between fair use and infringement is subjective and takes nuance to discern. The owners of intellectual property owe it to themselves to make the investment of qualified counsel <span style="font-style: italic;">before</span> they find themselves in court. As the saying goes: an ounce of prevention is worth a pound of cure.</p> <p>To learn more about how we can help you, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Contact.shtml">click here</a>.&nbsp;</p> <p><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="120" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/iva.jpg" alt="iva.jpg" /></p> <p><em><strong>IVA RUKELJ</strong><strong> </strong></em><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Attorneys/Iva-Rukelj.shtml"><br /> 212-206-9399 <br /> </a><a href="/E-mail.shtml">Email me</a></p> <p><span style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"></span></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What Do Chevrons, Stripes & Romance Have in Common? A US Supreme Court Decision!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/05/what-do-chevrons-stripes-romance-have-in-common-a-us-supreme-court-decision.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2618446</id>
  <published>2017-05-29T18:37:02Z</published>
  <updated>2017-06-12T17:13:57Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[If you thought that US Supreme Court justices lacked romantic proclivities, you're wrong! Some months ago, in a conversation between the justices about a very important copyright issue involving fashion, Justice Stephen Breyer stated, "The clothes on the hanger...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Iva Rukelj]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Copyright" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="copyrightissue" label="Copyright Issue" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="designpatents" label="Design Patents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="fashionindustry" label="Fashion Industry" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="starathletica" label="Star Athletica" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="ussupremecour" label="US Supreme Cour" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="varsitybrands" label="Varsity Brands" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/05/what-do-chevrons-stripes-romance-have-in-common-a-us-supreme-court-decision.shtml"><img style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" class="mt-image-center" height="266" width="400" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/05/What Do Chevrons Stripes Romance Have in Common A US Supreme Court Decision DPLIC 21972777-thumb-500x333-86360-thumb-400x266-86340.jpg" alt="Thumbnail image for What Do Chevrons Stripes Romance Have in Common A US Supreme Court Decision by Bill Samuels" /></a></p> <p>If you thought that US Supreme Court justices lacked romantic proclivities, you're wrong!</p> <p>Some months ago, in a conversation between the justices about a very important copyright issue involving fashion, Justice Stephen Breyer stated, "The clothes on the hanger do nothing. The clothes on the woman do everything." Justice Elena Kagan immediately interjected with, "That's so romantic!"</p> <p>Romantic or not, the justices were determining whether or not a feature of a useful article is protectable under Section 101 of the Copyright Act.&nbsp;</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p><em><strong>Star Athletica, LLC v. Varsity Brands, Inc.</strong></em></p> <p>This case involves two large manufacturers and distributors who compete in the cheerleading apparel industry.</p> <p>Star Athletica, the petitioner, created a new cheerleading uniform in 2010. The stripes, chevrons, zig zags, and color blocks are all part of the description of the uniform in dispute. Varsity Brands sued for copyright infringement; Varsity owns a copyright registration for a two-dimensional cheerleader uniform drawing and photo.</p> <p>The case was first heard in the United States District Court for Tennessee. That court decided that Varsity's design cannot apply, because it is a uniform and the design could not be conceptually separated from the utilitarian aspect of the objects themselves.</p> <p>However, the United States Court of Appeals for the 6th Circuit reversed that decision, finding that the design is copyrightable. This reversal resulted in a petition to the US Supreme Court.</p> <p>This case has prompted a lot of conversation and initiatives about whether you can protect a&nbsp;certain design, especially in the fashion industry. Traditionally, the protection for the fashion industry was offered by design patents in addition to trademark protection for the brand. Design patents give protection to a certain design if there is a novelty, which is hard to prove.</p> <p>In <em>Star Athletica, LLC v. Varsity Brands, Inc.</em><strong>,</strong> the Supreme Court held that "a feature incorporated into the design of a useful article is eligible for copyright protection only if the feature (1) can be perceived as a two- or three-dimensional work of art separate from the useful article, and (2) would qualify as a protectable pictorial, graphic, or sculptural work--either on its own or fixed in some tangible medium of expression--if it were imagined separately from the useful article into which it is incorporated." <em>Star Athletica, L.L.C. v. Varsity Brands, Inc.</em>, 137 S. Ct. 1002, 1005, 197 L. Ed. 2d 354 (2017).</p> <p>Applying copyrights to three-dimensional useful articles, i.e. clothing, high-end fashion designers will get closer protection for their products that get knocked off by smaller players even before their product hits the stores. This decision brings a new standard to the forefront of the fashion industry.</p> <p>And with this decision, the Supreme Court case on "romance" is adjudicated!</p> <p>Please <a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Contact.shtml">contact us</a> with thoughts or questions.&nbsp;</p> <p><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="120" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/iva.jpg" alt="iva.jpg" /></p> <p><em><strong>IVA RUKELJ</strong><strong> </strong></em><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Attorneys/Iva-Rukelj.shtml"><br /> 212-206-9399 <br /> </a><a href="/E-mail.shtml">Email me</a></p> <p><span style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"></span></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Rumblings from the UK: Staying Safe During Brexit]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/05/rumblings-from-the-uk-staying-safe-during-brexit.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2580750</id>
  <published>2017-05-02T16:51:35Z</published>
  <updated>2017-05-02T18:48:33Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Recent word from colleagues in the United Kingdom is that while European Union trademark filings and registrations still cover the UK, with Brexit underway the best bet these days is to file for EU coverage and UK coverage if the...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Bill Samuels]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Brexit" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Recent word from colleagues in the United Kingdom is that while European Union trademark filings and registrations still cover the UK, with Brexit underway the best bet these days is to file for EU coverage <i>and</i> UK coverage if the UK is a target for your business.&nbsp;</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>This is not to say that EU marks will not be honored in the UK in some fashion-the point is that with the current Brexit-generated uncertainty the safest plan is to secure intellectual property under UK IP laws to have confidence as to how that intellectual property will be treated.</p> <p>This is not an emergency, but it is an inevitability. Consider your coverage, your business, use of your IP, develop a plan, and implement it. Contact us any time to discuss.</p> <p>By: Bill Samuels, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/E-mail.shtml?guid=U4dE1fa50BlHZO7CpK+RKv2bS+wwniDvqMMX70SrgTQ1WTpvJJRfjsWAEe6x96pwOqfuWSc8S5rQxXIN8peT2kI2Y05vNTcDuOYavnc2cwfTHRQOw0GZuqcVFaG0i9rlbA9YF2Eh4q5x+oehshS8ggtGHM70RUnMLzwV8MZrxs0=&attorneyName=William%20R.%20Samuels">bill@wrsamuelslaw.com</a></p> <p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2016/11/bill samuels-thumb-150x112-78738.jpg"><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="112" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/01/bill samuels-thumb-150x112-78738-thumb-150x112-80935.jpg" alt="Thumbnail image for bill samuels.jpg" /></a></p> <p><em><strong>WILLIAM R. SAMUELS</strong></em><br /> <strong>212-206-9399 </strong><br /> <a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/E-mail.shtml?guid=U4dE1fa50BlHZO7CpK+RKv2bS+wwniDvqMMX70SrgTQ1WTpvJJRfjsWAEe6x96pwOqfuWSc8S5rQxXIN8peT2kI2Y05vNTcDuOYavnc2cwfTHRQOw0GZuqcVFaG0i9rlbA9YF2Eh4q5x+oehshS8ggtGHM70RUnMLzwV8MZrxs0=&attorneyName=William%20R.%20Samuels"><strong>Email me</strong></a>&nbsp;</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Technically, "Data Are Still Data"]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/04/technically-data-are-still-data.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2567839</id>
  <published>2017-04-19T18:47:24Z</published>
  <updated>2017-04-19T19:01:56Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[In Clarilogic v. FormFree Holdings, the Court Of Appeals upheld the District Court for the Southern District of California holding that the claims of U.S. Patent Application No. 8,762,243 ('243 Patent) are ineligible under 35 U.S.C. § 101 because they...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By John Laurence]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Patents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="intellectualproperty" label="Intellectual Property" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="patentlaw" label="Patent Law" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="patentprotection" label="Patent Protection" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/%20Technically%20Data%20Are%20Still%20Data%20DPLIC%20122862168_s-2015.jpg"><img style="float: right; margin: 0 0 20px 20px;" class="mt-image-right" height="187" width="250" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/04/ Technically Data Are Still Data DPLIC 122862168_s-2015-thumb-250x187-84859.jpg" alt=" Technically Data Are Still Data DPLIC 122862168_s-2015.jpg" /></a>In <em>Clarilogic v. FormFree Holdings,</em> the Court Of Appeals upheld the District Court for the Southern District of California holding that the claims of U.S. Patent Application No. 8,762,243 ('243 Patent) are ineligible under 35 U.S.C. § 101 because they are directed to an abstract idea and contain no additional elements that transform the nature of the claims into a patent-eligible application of the abstract idea.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The '243 Patent is entitled "System and Method for Electronic Account Certification and Enhance Credit Reporting." Generally, the claimed computer implemented system gathers a potential borrower's financial data from a third party, applies an "algorithm engine" to the gathered data, and outputs a report. The claims do not recite any specific rules implemented by the "algorithm engine." Rather, the rules implemented by the "algorithm engine" are obtained from third parties who define rules used to identify information.</p> <p>The Court noted that when "the focus of the claims" is "on collecting information, analyzing it, and displaying certain results of the collection and analysis," the claims are directed to an abstract idea. Moreover, claiming an algorithm engine without defining a specific set of rules implemented by an algorithm engine performing the analysis is the "height of abstraction."</p> <p>Defendant <em>Form Free</em> argued that its invention is "transformative" and thus eligible for patent protection. Specifically, <em>Form Free</em> argued that the invention is "transformative" because it takes in financial data and outputs a report. The Court disagreed, stating that the claimed method simply changes the way electronic information is displayed using an unknown and unclaimed algorithm engine. As such, without any limitations in how the gathered data are changed, there is no "transformative" effect. After all, as the Court stated, "Data are still data."</p> <p>A business method claim, or any other type of method claim, must specifically define all the method stops including those that help make the method novel. Single processing data to arrive at an output is simply too abstract to be patent eligible subject matter.&nbsp;</p> <p><a href="/Attorneys/John-C-Laurence.shtml"><img alt="Thumbnail image for john laurence.jpg" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2016/09/john laurence-thumb-150x112-75969-thumb-150x112-75945.jpg" width="150" height="112" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></a></p> <p><strong><strong>JOHN LAURENCE</strong></strong></p> <p><strong><strong>212-206-9399</strong></strong></p> <p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Contact.shtml" target="_blank">Email Me</a></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Illinois Church Adds Zeros to Adidas' Legal Bills]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/03/illinois-church-adds-zeros-to-adidas-legal-bills.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2525700</id>
  <published>2017-03-20T18:36:39Z</published>
  <updated>2017-03-26T20:47:38Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[We admit we are talking about Adidas a lot lately, but that is because (i) we truly love their gear, and (ii) they have really been active. After some bruising encounters with United States trademark law, Adidas SA recently...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Iva Rukelj]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Trademarks" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="adidaslegalbills" label="Adidas' Legal Bills" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="illinoischurch" label="Illinois Church" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="unitedstatestrademarklaw" label="United States Trademark Law" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/03/illinois-church-adds-zeros-to-adidas-legal-bills.shtml"><img style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" class="mt-image-center" height="393" width="500" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/03/Illinois Church Adds Zeros to Adidas Legal Bills DPLIC 65962283-thumb-500x393-84142.jpg" alt="Illinois Church Adds Zeros to Adidas Legal Bills by Iva Rukelj " /></a></p> <p>We admit we are talking about Adidas a lot lately, but that is because (i) we truly love their gear, and (ii) they have really been active. After some bruising encounters with United States trademark law, Adidas SA recently found itself on the ropes again, this time at the hands of a church in Zion, Illinois. The marks in question are a study in phonics:&nbsp;</p> <p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>ADIZERO</strong> running shoes by Adidas vs. <strong>ADD A ZERO</strong> hats by Christian Faith Fellowship.&nbsp;</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>In 2005 a small congregation by the name of Christian Faith Fellowship, based in Zion, Illinois, registered a wordmark and a logo mark with the United States Patent and Trademark Office for hats emblazoned with the phrase "ADD A ZERO." The hats were not a big seller, with only two of them recorded as being sold-critically, with one being paid for by a check drawn on a Wisconsin bank.</p> <p>In 2009, Adidas was ready to roll out its new, lightweight running shoes, which it dubbed "ADIZERO." Upon petitioning the USPTO for protection, Adidas' claim was denied based on the the existence of Christian Faith Fellowship's prior registration. The USPTO found there to be a likelihood of confusion.</p> <p>Adidas appealed this decision to the Trademark Trial and Appeal Board (TTAB), arguing that Christian Faith Fellowship's hats are not a source identifier and that they had sold a very limited number of the hats without showing any significant use in commerce which generally denotes <span style="font-style: italic;">interstate</span> commerce. Christian Faith Fellowship then produced the Wisconsin bank check mentioned earlier, claiming that it indeed had engaged in interstate commerce, even if only for two sales. The TTAB ultimately decided in favor of Adidas, citing the small number of hats that were sold.</p> <p>Christian Faith Fellowship appealed the TTAB's decision and found itself battling Adidas before the Federal Circuit. In an effort to get the case thrown out, Adidas argued for a <span style="font-style: italic;">de minimis</span> exception because only two hats had been sold, and Christian Faith Fellowship did not truly engage in interstate commerce. Its argument was denied and the court went on to nullify the TTAB's decision because case law was clear that the sale of two hats was sufficient to establish interstate commerce.</p> <p>The circuit court remanded the case back to the TTAB where it is currently under review.</p> <p>This case is interesting because many practitioners disagree with the Federal Circuit's ruling. They say it sets a very low standard for interstate commerce and sets up too many obstacles for large producers of trademarked products. What's your ruling?&nbsp;</p> <p><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="120" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/iva.jpg" alt="iva.jpg" /></p> <p><em><strong>IVA RUKELJ</strong><strong> </strong></em><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Attorneys/Iva-Rukelj.shtml"><br /> 212-206-9399 <br /> </a><a href="/E-mail.shtml">Email me</a></p> <p><span style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"></span></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[The USPTO Made a New Years' Resolution & It Impacts You]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/02/the-uspto-made-a-new-years-resolution-it-impacts-you.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2467503</id>
  <published>2017-02-14T17:15:00Z</published>
  <updated>2017-02-15T14:14:07Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The USPTO and Trademark Trial and Appeal Board ("TTAB") joined the rest of us in attempting to improve with a New Year's resolution. However, instead of already giving up on gym membership plans, the USPTO has taken 2017 by...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Jerry Jakubovic]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Trademarks" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="trademarktrialandappealboardttab" label="Trademark Trial and Appeal Board (TTAB)" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="uspto" label="USPTO" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/02/the-uspto-made-a-new-years-resolution-it-impacts-you.shtml"><img style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" class="mt-image-center" height="300" width="300" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/02/The USPTO Made a New Years Resolution it Impacts You Dplic 46336465-thumb-500x500-82585-thumb-300x300-82574.jpg" alt="Thumbnail image for The USPTO Made a New Years Resolution it Impacts You Dplic 46336465.jpg" /></a></p> <p>The USPTO and Trademark Trial and Appeal Board ("TTAB") joined the rest of us in attempting to improve with a New Year's resolution. However, instead of already giving up on gym membership plans, the USPTO has taken 2017 by storm with an emphasis on digital efficiency, some rule changes, and everyone's favorite, increased fees. &nbsp;</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Whether you are a seasoned practitioner, or an individual navigating the trademark thickets yourself, you should bookmark this page for reference now that January 14, 2017, rule changes are in effect.</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Efficiency</span></p> <p>It's not very often that one hears the words "efficient" and "government" uttered in the same breath. But come January 14, we <span style="font-style: italic;">should </span>have fewer action items when dealing with the USPTO and TTAB in general.</p> <p>Thanks to the USPTO's 2017 resolution to save the environment, or in the alternative, settle a grudge with the paper industry:</p> <ul> <li> <p>E-Filing is no longer preferred, but expected and mandatory with the TTAB.</p> <ul> <li> <p>This requirement appears to only be waivable via petitioning the office.</p> </li> <li> <p>This includes correspondence between the parties (i.e., say goodbye to the 5-day snail mail grace period and hello to composing, even more, e-mails).</p> </li> </ul> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>The TTAB is taking service requirements off our plates.</p> <ul> <li> <p>This thankfully relieves us of cancellation and opposition service duties for initial pleadings, replacing first-class mail with a link embedded in an e-mail sent to other parties to the matter.</p> </li> <li> <p>This is also an opportunity to make sure that all of the contact information you may be responsible for is up-to-date.</p> </li> </ul> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>You and/or your clients get to give the government more money!</p> <ul> <li> <p>A total of 10 TTAB-related fees will be adjusted. Six fees for initiating a proceeding will increase, depending upon whether filed electronically or on paper.</p> </li> <li> <p>After an initial request for extension, there are now four new fees established for electronic and paper-filed requests to further extend time to file a notice of opposition.</p> </li> <li> <p>There are fees for extensions of time to oppose billed per application rather than per class.</p> </li> <li> <p>Moreover, the per-class fee for an initial application for registration filed on paper is going from $375 to $600 per mark, per class (supporting anti-paper conspiracy theorists).</p> </li> <li> <p>A full list of fee changes is provided&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://www.uspto.gov/trademark/fees-payment-information/trademark-fee-changes">here</a> by the USPTO.</p> </li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Testimony</span></p> <p>Relevant to a smaller segment of readers but important nonetheless, there has been some tweaking to evidentiary procedure. One huge takeaway in this department is that witness testimony can now be submitted by affidavit alone. The hassles of live depositions should subside, however:</p> <ul> <li> <p>Live depositions are still an available cross-examination tool for opposing parties in examining a witness affidavit;</p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>Notices of reliance have had their capacity expanded to record registrations and introduce supporting digital content;</p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>Of concern is that the efficiency seemingly sought after by the USPTO may be undermined by overwhelming amounts of evidence likely to now be submitted, delaying proceeding considerably.</p> </li> </ul> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Discovery</span></p> <p>Gone are the days of unlimited requests. We now have the number "75" restraining our decision making when it comes time to talk document production and admission strategy, and further (likely in the name of efficiency), the discovery period is now a bright line six-month ordeal.</p> <p>As always, you should carefully read or ask your local counsel about&nbsp;<a href="https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/documents/2017Rulechangehighlights.pdf">the new rules which can be found here in their entirety</a>.</p> <p>With the digitalization and constant technological progress of society, new and interesting trademark requests will continue to appear and challenge existing definitions and requirements. We at W. R. Samuels Law will continue to keep our ears pressed to the ground in order to detect new trends in trademark law before they have an impact on our clients. For more information, <a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Contact.shtml">contact us</a>.</p> <p>Law Clerk Jerry Jakubovic is a 3L at New York Law School and a current Law Clerk at W.R. Samuels Law.</p> <p><i>JERRY JAKUBOVIC</i></p> <p>212-206-9399</p> <p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Contact.shtml">Email me</a></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Barcelona and Adidas Reach Detente]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/02/barcelona-and-adidas-reach-detente.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2464409</id>
  <published>2017-02-13T16:40:03Z</published>
  <updated>2017-02-13T20:55:14Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[It looks like Barcelona and Adidas have reached a deal to keep the Football Club's stripes off the USPTO register and Adidas's options open for future enforcement....]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Bill Samuels]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Trademarks" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="adidas" label="Adidas" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="barcelona" label="Barcelona" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/Barcelona%20and%20Adidas%20Reach%20Detente%20DPLIC%2012236757.jpg"><img alt="Barcelona and Adidas Reach Detente DPLIC 12236757.jpg" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/02/Barcelona and Adidas Reach Detente DPLIC 12236757-thumb-500x481-82535.jpg" width="400" height="381" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></a></p> <p>It looks like Barcelona and Adidas have reached a deal to keep the Football Club's stripes off the USPTO register and Adidas's options open for future enforcement.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>On February 7, 2017, Adidas AG, its affiliates, and Futbol Club Barcelona, filed a <a target="_blank" href="http://ttabvue.uspto.gov/ttabvue/v?pno=91230938&pty=OPP&eno=7"><span style="font-style: italic;">Mutually Consented Motion to Withdraw Application And Dismiss Opposition Without Prejudice</span></a><span style="font-style: italic;">.</span></p> <p>Next up is a response from the TTAB. Developing...</p> <p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2016/11/bill samuels-thumb-150x112-78738.jpg"><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="112" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/01/bill samuels-thumb-150x112-78738-thumb-150x112-80935.jpg" alt="Thumbnail image for bill samuels.jpg" /></a></p> <p><em><strong>WILLIAM R. SAMUELS</strong></em><br /> <strong>212-206-9399 </strong><br /> <a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/E-mail.shtml?guid=U4dE1fa50BlHZO7CpK+RKv2bS+wwniDvqMMX70SrgTQ1WTpvJJRfjsWAEe6x96pwOqfuWSc8S5rQxXIN8peT2kI2Y05vNTcDuOYavnc2cwfTHRQOw0GZuqcVFaG0i9rlbA9YF2Eh4q5x+oehshS8ggtGHM70RUnMLzwV8MZrxs0=&attorneyName=William%20R.%20Samuels"><strong>Email me</strong></a>&nbsp;</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Stripes: Adidas Files Notice of Opposition to Soccer Club FC Barcelona's Trademark]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/01/stripes-adidas-files-notice-of-opposition-to-soccer-club-fc-barcelonas-trademark.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2017:/blog//73171.2409181</id>
  <published>2017-01-08T13:40:42Z</published>
  <updated>2017-01-10T15:15:47Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The most interesting grudge match in professional soccer this season isn't between FC Barcelona and Real Madrid, but rather the intellectual property lawyers representing Barcelona and footwear giant Adidas. "Kit" sponsoring--sponsoring the uniforms of a team--is a highly competitive...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Iva Rukelj]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Trademarks" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="adidas" label="Adidas" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="intellectualpropertylawyers" label="Intellectual Property Lawyers" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="nike" label="Nike" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="noticeofopposition" label="Notice of Opposition" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="soccerclubfcbarcelonastrademark" label="Soccer Club FC Barcelona's Trademark" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="unitedstatespatentandtrademarkofficeuspto" label="United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO)" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2017/01/stripes-adidas-files-notice-of-opposition-to-soccer-club-fc-barcelonas-trademark.shtml"><img style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" class="mt-image-center" height="313" width="500" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/01/Stripes Adidas Files Notice of Opposition to Soccer Club F DPLIC 88938876-thumb-500x313-80984.jpg" alt="Stripes: Adidas Files Notice of Opposition to Soccer Club FC Barcelona's Trademark by Iva Rukelj " /></a></p> <p>The most interesting grudge match in professional soccer this season isn't between FC Barcelona and Real Madrid, but rather the intellectual property lawyers representing Barcelona and footwear giant Adidas.</p> <p>"Kit" sponsoring--sponsoring the uniforms of a team--is a highly competitive business dominated by Nike and Adidas. For example, Adidas pays top-rated Manchester United €83.5 million a season for the privilege of providing uniforms emblazoned with its three-stripe logo.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Never one to shy away from defending its brand, Adidas opened a new front in its rivalry with Nike the day after Nike signed a deal for a kit design and sponsorship with FC Barcelona at a record-breaking €155 million a season. Adidas took umbrage with the new kit design, which features seven stripes; four blue and three red, in an alternating sequence with smaller, vertical stripes within each of the larger ones. <span style="font-style: italic;">Note: FC Barcelona's jerseys have always featured some kind of stripe pattern since the inception of the club.</span></p> <p>This clash of sportswear titans is currently unfolding at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO), Opposition No. 91230938. FC Barcelona's 2016 jersey design having already attained a trademark, Adidas filed a notice of opposition with the USPTO. It contends that its emblematic three-stripe mark precedes Barcelona's mark and therefore makes it invalid.</p> <p>Indeed, Adidas has been using its three-stripe pattern in the United States and worldwide since 1952 for footwear and 1967 for apparel. Adidas claims it is trying to protect the goodwill it has worked to establish its brand since then, and if Barcelona's Nike-sponsored design were to stand, Adidas' goodwill would be diluted.</p> <p>As mentioned earlier, Adidas is no stranger to the legal system when it comes to protecting its mark. Recently Adidas took action against fashion designer Marc Jacobs and clothing store Forever 21 for apparel that featured four stripes and three stripes, respectively, along the sleeves. That said, Adidas also has a history of working constructively with other designers, including its Yeezy line of sneakers made in conjunction with Kanye West.</p> <p>This development is recent and the adjudication at the USPTO is ongoing. Stay tuned!</p> <p><span style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"></span></p> <p><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="120" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/iva.jpg" alt="iva.jpg" /></p> <p><em><strong>IVA RUKELJ</strong><strong> </strong></em><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Attorneys/Iva-Rukelj.shtml"><br /> 212-206-9399 <br /> </a><a href="/E-mail.shtml">Email me</a></p> <p><span style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"></span></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[NY State Bar IP Section Annual Meeting]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2016/12/ny-state-bar-ip-section-annual-meeting.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2016:/blog//73171.2398502</id>
  <published>2016-12-29T22:55:54Z</published>
  <updated>2016-12-29T23:00:21Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Bill Samuels is Program Chair of the Intellectual Property Law Section Annual Meeting on January 24, 2017, at the New York Hilton Midtown, NYC. Topics will include IP issues in social media, data and privacy concerns, design protections, IP litigation,...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Bill Samuels]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Bill Samuels is Program Chair of the Intellectual Property Law Section Annual Meeting on January 24, 2017, at the New York Hilton Midtown, NYC. Topics will include IP issues in social media, data and privacy concerns, design protections, IP litigation, and damages, as well as a review of IP cases in 2016 and what to watch for in 2017. For more information or to attend, go to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nysba.org/am2017IPS/ ">http://www.nysba.org/am2017IPS/&nbsp;&nbsp;</a></p>]]>
    
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[A Primer on Non-Traditional Trademarks]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2016/12/a-primer-on-non-traditional-trademarks.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2016:/blog//73171.2392958</id>
  <published>2016-12-26T17:58:04Z</published>
  <updated>2017-01-10T20:16:36Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[A trademark is a "source identifier." That is, a trademark generally is a word, phrase, symbol, design or a combination of words, phrases, symbols, or designs that identify and distinguishes the source of the goods of one party from...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Iva Rukelj]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Trademarks" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="christianlouboutinshoes" label="Christian Louboutin Shoes" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="nontraditionaltrademarks" label="Non-Traditional Trademarks" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="primer" label="Primer" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2016/12/a-primer-on-non-traditional-trademarks.shtml"><img alt="A Primer on Non Traditional Trademarks by Iva Rukelj " src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/01/A Primer on Non Traditional Trademarks dplic 123240228-thumb-499x333-81028.jpg" width="499" height="333" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></a></p> <p>A trademark is a "source identifier." That is, a trademark generally is a word, phrase, symbol, design or a combination of words, phrases, symbols, or designs that identify and distinguishes the source of the goods of one party from those of others, and can be used to indicate the source of goods and services. The most recognizable trademarks are usually wordmarks or logos also known as traditional trademarks.</p> <p>Non-traditional trademarks include colors, motions, sounds, scents, and even shapes. Obtaining protection for non-traditional marks can be challenging, but not impossible.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Color</span></p> <p>A color itself can be registered as a trademark, not connected with words or any kind of graphic design. Examples of trademarked colors include UPS and its brown color in US Reg. No. 2,901,090 for "transportation and delivery of personal property by air and motor vehicle," with the following description of the mark: "The mark consists of the color chocolate brown, which is the approximate equivalent of Pantone Matching System 462C, as applied to the entire surface of vehicles and uniforms. The mark consists of the color brown alone. The broken lines indicate the position of the mark and do not form part of the mark".</p> <p>Another famous color mark is Tiffany's unique "robin's egg" shade of blue, for boxes (US Reg. No. 2,359,351), shopping bags (US Reg. No. 2,416,795), and on the cover of catalogs (US Reg. No. 2,416,794). And, of course, many know about Christian Louboutin shoes with their red soles, covered under US Reg. No. 3,361,597, for women's high-fashion designer footwear:</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Motion</span></p> <p>Some moving images that combine colors, sounds, and product design, but also the movement of a person that is not a static gesture but a flow of images. A good example is a UK mark (UK00002607608) for a 3-D yoga app.</p> <p>In the US, if the mark has motion, the drawing may depict a single point in the movement, or the drawing may depict up to five freeze frames showing various points in the movement, whichever best depicts the commercial impression of the mark. The applicant must also describe the mark. 37 C.F.R. §2.52(b)(3).</p> <p>Another challenge applicants of motion marks need to consider is providing an appropriate specimen of use. This challenge is greater for applicants who seek to register their mark for use in connection with goods. A motion mark, by its nature, is unable to be affixed on goods (or packaging). In this case, by rule, a specimen will be in electronic format. The USPTO's Trademark Manual of Examining Procedure (TMEP) governs the submission of specimens for motion marks. It provides that for a motion mark "an acceptable specimen should show the entire repetitive motion in order to depict the commercial impression conveyed by the mark (e.g., a video clip, a series of still photos, or a series of screenshots)."</p> <p>For specimens for services, Section 1301.04(a) of the TMEP requires that "the specimen must show the use of the mark in a manner that would be perceived by potential purchasers as identifying the applicant's services and indicating their source."</p> <p>An example of a motion service mark is US Reg. No. 2,710,415, for a "Duck March," for hotel-related services.</p> <p>A description of the mark is: "The mark consists of the live visual and motion elements of The Peabody Duck March as performed at the Peabody Hotel, only one segment of which is depicted in line art in the drawing. The motion elements include the red carpet being rolled out, the appearance of the ducks and uniformed Duckmaster at the elevator door, and the march of the ducks down the red carpet, up the steps, and into the fountain where they begin swimming. The mark also includes the fanfare in reverse sequence." The specimen consists of screenshots of a video recording of the marching ducks.</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Sound</span></p> <p>For musical tones, a sound can be described using sheet music, but other types of sounds have to be described verbally. For example, "Let's get ready to rumble," Michael Buffer's famous phrase he is known for bellowing before a boxing match, is described as: "The mark consists of a sound mark comprising the spoken words 'LET'S GET READY TO RUMBLE'."</p> <p>Another good example of a sound mark is the roar of the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.uspto.gov/trademarks/soundmarks/73553567.mp3">MGM's lion Leo</a>, described as "The Mark comprises of a lion roaring".</p> <p>Or consider the famous <a target="_blank" href="https://www.uspto.gov/trademarks/soundmarks/75326989.mp3">call of the character Tarzan</a>, described as: "...the sound of the famous Tarzan yell. The mark is a yell consisting of a series of approximately ten sounds, alternating between the chest and falsetto registers of the voice, as follows:</p> <ol> <li> <p>a semi-long sound in the chest register;</p> </li> <li> <p>a short sound up an interval of one octave plus a fifth from the preceding sound;</p> </li> <li> <p>a short sound down a Major 3rd from the preceding sound;</p> </li> <li> <p>a short sound up a Major 3rd from the preceding sound;</p> </li> <li> <p>a long sound down one octave plus a Major 3rd from the preceding sound;</p> </li> <li> <p>a short sound up one octave from the preceding sound;</p> </li> <li> <p>a short sound up a Major 3rd from the preceding sound;</p> </li> <li> <p>a short sound down a Major 3rd from the preceding sound;</p> </li> <li> <p>a short sound up a Major 3rd from the preceding sound;</p> </li> <li> <p>a long sound down an octave plus a fifth from the preceding sound."</p> </li> </ol> <p>An example of a sound that could <span style="font-style: italic;">not </span>be registered is the revving of a Harley-Davidson motorcycle. Harley-Davidson tried for years to register the sound but eventually had to drop the matter because it was not possible to describe the sound adequately with words.</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Scent</span></p> <p>Specific smells associated with particular goods or services can be trademarked, however, they cannot merely be the natural smell of the product. It has to be some kind of scent that a company wants to use as a source identifier or indicator for their product. For example, there is a cherry scent for synthetic lubricants that is registered in the US-or one of my favorites for retail store services featuring jewelry, diamond jewelry, gemstone jewelry, etc. is described as: "The mark consists of the scent of chocolate." Diamonds and chocolate, brilliant!</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Taste</span></p> <p>Taste can also be registered as a mark, but describing taste can be difficult because sometimes it is a challenge to actually distinguish between the flavor of the product and something that is connected to the product but not necessarily its own natural flavor.</p> <p>The famous example is the pharmaceutical company Eli Lilly's attempt to register the taste of artificial strawberries in the EU. The application was rejected (case R 120/2001-2) because: "Any manufacturer...is entitled to add the flavor of artificial strawberries to those products for the purpose of disguising any unpleasant taste that they might otherwise have or simply for the purpose of making them pleasant to taste... Moreover, the taste is unlikely to be perceived by consumers as a trademark; they are far more likely to assume that it is intended to disguise the unpleasant taste of the product..."</p> <p>Another challenge is whether taste can act as a trademark (indicators of source) because (usually) consumers only taste goods <span style="font-style: italic;">after</span> purchase, as opposed to before and during the commercial transaction.</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Touch</span></p> <p>When a touch or "tactile" trademark is granted, it can be either the product itself or its packaging. For example, the packaging may have some kind of particular sensation to the touch which is distinguishable from others.</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">New Developments in Nontraditional Marks</span></p> <p>While considered and used throughout the world, non-traditional trademarks were historically difficult to obtain in the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2016/08/brexit-trademark-concerns.shtml">European Union</a> (<span style="font-weight: bold;">European Union Intellectual Property Office</span>) because a graphical representation of the product had to be included in the application. This would obviously be difficult to do with a perfume or a non-musical sound. Beginning in October of 2017 that will no longer be the case; applicants will be able to protect sound, color, shape, and movement without the requirement of a graphical representation. Instead, the standard will be whether or not the mark enables the public and relevant authorities to determine the clear and precise subject matter.</p> <p>With the digitalization and constant technological progress of society, new and interesting trademark requests will continue to appear and challenge existing definitions and requirements. We at W. R. Samuels Law will continue to keep our ears pressed to the ground in order to detect new trends in trademark law before they have an impact on our clients. For more information, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Contact.shtml">contact us</a>.</p> <p>Bill Samuels is Program Chair of the Intellectual Property Law Section Annual Meeting on January 24, 2017, at the New York Hilton Midtown, NYC. Topics will include IP issues in social media, data and privacy concerns, design protections, IP litigation, and damages, as well as a review of IP cases in 2016 and what to watch for in 2017. For more information or to attend, go to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nysba.org/am2017IPS/">http://www.nysba.org/am2017IPS/</a>&nbsp;</p> <p><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="120" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/iva.jpg" alt="iva.jpg" /></p> <p><em><strong>IVA RUKELJ</strong><strong> </strong></em><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Attorneys/Iva-Rukelj.shtml"><br /> 212-206-9399 <br /> </a><a href="/E-mail.shtml">Email me</a></p> <p><span style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"></span></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Bill Samuels to Moderate NY State Bar Panel: "Trademarks, Domain Names, and Cybersquatting"]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2016/12/ill-samuels-to-moderate-ny-state-bar-panel-trademarks-domain-names-and-cybersquatting.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2016:/blog//73171.2359013</id>
  <published>2016-12-05T22:18:13Z</published>
  <updated>2016-12-29T14:42:28Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[On December 6, 2016, Bill Samuels will moderate a panel for the Trademark Committee of the NY State Bar IP Section on the topic of trademarks and issues that arise on the Internet, namely domain names and cybersquatting. The panel...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By Bill Samuels]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Trademarks" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>On December 6, 2016, Bill Samuels will moderate a panel for the Trademark Committee of the NY State Bar IP Section on the topic of trademarks and issues that arise on the Internet, namely domain names and cybersquatting. The panel will discuss and evaluate current practical considerations in asserting and defending cybersquatting claims.&nbsp;</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Bill Samuels: 2016 New York Metro Super Lawyers and Rising Star Selection:</span></p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;"></span>For the fourth year in a row, Bill Samuels has been selected as a New York Metro Super Lawyers and Rising Star. The 2016 New York Metro Super Lawyers Rising Stars list includes no more than 2.5 percent of peer-nominated and evaluated candidates.</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">W.R.S. Law Associate Spoke at Croatian Association of Women in the Legal Profession:</span></p> <p>Iva Rukelj is an intellectual property associate and litigation specialist at W.R. Samuels Law, as well as Vice President for the Croatian American Bar Association. This past September 2016 she spoke at the inaugural event for the Croatian Association of Women in the Legal Profession (<a href="http://www.huzupp.com/en/">http://www.huzupp.com/en/</a>). After a years of European and Croatian practice, and time working on US and international intellectual property matters while based in New York City, Ms. Rukelj took the opportunity to discuss the importance of intellectual property in the international arena and women's growth and real contributions in the space in the US, Croatia, and beyond.</p> <p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Bill Samuels Moderates NY Bar Panel: "Venturing Forward: Issues Facing Start-Up Companies:"</span></p> <p>Partner Bill Samuels recently moderated a panel at the NY State Bar IP Section 2016 Fall Meeting concerning IP issues facing start-up companies. On November 10 Bill joined investor, entrepreneur, and legal industry panelists to discuss core considerations in IP protections and strategies for early-stage companies.&nbsp;</p>]]>
    
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[USPTO Issues Memorandum on Recent Subject Matter Eligibility Decision]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2016/11/uspto-issues-memorandum-on-recent-subject-matter-eligibility-decision.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2016:/blog//73171.2318489</id>
  <published>2016-11-09T17:34:46Z</published>
  <updated>2017-01-10T14:52:56Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[On November 2nd, the USPTO issued new guidance to Patent Examiners regarding § 101 subject matter eligibility. The memorandum (USPTO-McRO-Bascom-Memo-1.pdf) provides guidance based on Federal Circuit decisions issued since the office's most recent, May 2016, update. The memo includes...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By John Laurence]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Patents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="patentexaminers" label="Patent Examiners" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="uspto" label="USPTO" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2016/11/uspto-issues-memorandum-on-recent-subject-matter-eligibility-decision.shtml"><img style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" class="mt-image-center" height="500" width="500" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2017/01/USPTO Issues Memorandum on Recent Subject Matter Eligibility Decision Dplic 47206203-thumb-500x500-80991.jpg" alt="USPTO Issues Memorandum on Recent Subject Matter Eligibility Decision by John Laurence" /></a></p> <p>On November 2nd, the USPTO issued new guidance to Patent Examiners regarding § 101 subject matter eligibility. The memorandum (<a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/USPTO-McRo-Bascom-Memo-1.pdf">USPTO-McRO-Bascom-Memo-1.pdf</a>) provides guidance based on Federal Circuit decisions issued since the office's most recent, May 2016, update. The memo includes guidance based on the Federal Circuit's recent decisions in <span style="font-style: italic;">McRO, Inc. v. Bandai Namco Games</span>&nbsp;and <span style="font-style: italic;">BASCOM Global Internet v. AT&T Mobility</span> decisions.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>In <span style="font-style: italic;">McRO</span>, the Federal Circuit held that a method of automatic lip synchronization and facial expression animation using computer-implemented rules is patent eligible under 35 U.S.C. § 101 as being directed to an improvement in computer-related technology. The improvement was routed in a set of specific rules to set morph weights and transition parameters between phonemes. The court indicated that it was the incorporation of these specific rules in computer animation that provided the necessary improvement to the existing technological process. The memo notes that these specific rules, as explained in the specification, are not used by human artists which instead rely on subjective determinations to set forth the morph weights and the manipulation of the animated face to match pronounced phenomes.</p> <p>The memo suggests looking at (1) a teaching in the specification about how the claimed invention improves a computer or other technology or (2) a particular solution to a problem or a particular way to achieve a desired outcome defined by the claimed invention, as opposed to merely claiming the idea of a solution or outcome as possible indicators that a claim is directed to an improvement in computer-related technology.</p> <p>In <span style="font-style: italic;">BASCOM</span>, the Federal Circuit held that a system that includes the installation of a filtering tool at a specific location, remote from the end-users, with customizable filtering features specific to each end user is patent eligible under 35 U.S.C. § 101. The Court agreed that the additional elements including a generic computer, network, and Internet components did not amount to significantly more under step 2B of the USPTO's Subject Matter Eligibility Test when considered individually. However, the Court explained that the inventive concept may be found in the non-conventional and non-generic arrangement of the additional elements, namely the placement of customized filtering components.</p> <p>The memo suggests that examiners need to consider additional elements in combination, as well as individually&nbsp;when determining whether a claim as whole amounts to significantly more, as this requirement may be found in non-conventional and non-generic arrangement of known or conventional elements.</p> <p><a href="/Attorneys/John-C-Laurence.shtml"><img alt="Thumbnail image for john laurence.jpg" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2016/09/john laurence-thumb-150x112-75969-thumb-150x112-75945.jpg" width="150" height="112" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></a></p> <p><strong><strong>JOHN LAURENCE</strong></strong></p> <p><strong><strong>212-206-9399</strong></strong></p> <p><a href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Contact.shtml" target="_blank">Email Me</a></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Developing Requirements For Patentable Subject Matter]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/2016/09/developing-requirements-for-patentable-subject-matter.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.wrsamuelslaw.com,2016:/blog//73171.2230459</id>
  <published>2016-09-15T19:16:04Z</published>
  <updated>2016-11-10T04:12:46Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[In talking to clients whose patent applications involve software, it simply is not good enough to ask for as much specificity as possible to help remove the invention from the realm of an abstract idea and avoid an unpatentable...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[By John Laurence]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Patents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="electricpowergrid" label="Electric Power Grid" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="patentablesubjectmatter" label="Patentable Subject Matter" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><img alt="DevelopingRequirementsForPatentableSubjectMatter by John Laurence" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/images/Developing%20Requirements%20For%20Patentable%20Subject%20Matter%20DPLIC%2069537559.jpg" width="300" height="300" class="mt-image-right" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 20px 20px;" /></p> <p>In talking to clients whose patent applications involve software, it simply is not good enough to ask for as much specificity as possible to help remove the invention from the realm of an abstract idea and avoid an unpatentable subject matter rejection. Rather, it now seems that the required specificity must also be grounded in a "technical means" for implementing the software components. Of course, what this "technical means" encompasses is not necessarily easy to define.</p> <p>A recent decision from the Federal Circuit in<span style="font-style: italic;"><span style="font-weight: bold;"> Electric Power Group, LLC v. Alstom S.A</span></span>. does provide some helpful insight as to this "technical means." Case No. 2015-1778 (Fed. Cir. Aug. 1, 2016).</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The patents at issue involved systems and methods for performing real-time performance monitoring of an electric power grid by collecting data from multiple data sources, analyzing the data, and displaying results. Importantly, a majority of software developers will consider many of the recited steps as common building&nbsp;block of the trade, including:</p> <ul> <li> <p>receiving a plurality of data streams;</p> </li> <li> <p>detecting and analyzing events in real-time;</p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>displaying analysis results;</p> </li> <li> <p>displaying concurrent visualization of measurements;</p> </li> <li> <p>accumulating and updating the measurements from the date streams; and</p> </li> <li> <p>deriving a composite indicator of reliability.</p> </li> </ul> <p>In reviewing these steps, the court first clarified which of them simply do not qualify as a "technical means." Specifically, "the collection of information, including when limited to particular content, is considered abstract." <span style="font-style: italic;">Id</span> at 7. "The analysis of information by steps people go through in their minds, or by mathematical algorithm, without more, as essentially metal processes is considered abstract." <span style="font-style: italic;">Id.</span> "The mere presentation of results of abstract processes of collecting analyzing information, without more (such as identifying a particular tool for presentation), is considered abstract as an ancillary part of such collection and analysis." <span style="font-style: italic;">Id</span>.</p> <p>In view of these abstract elements, the court noted that the claims simply define "a process of gathering and analyzing information of a specified content" while not including "any particular assuredly inventive technology for performing these functions." <span style="font-style: italic;">Id</span> at 8. The court further clarified this distinction by comparing "computer-functionality improvements" on the one hand and "uses of existing computer tools in aid of processes focused on abstract ideas" on the other. <span style="font-style: italic;">Id</span>.</p> <p>So, what are these "technical means" which may provide for "computer-functionality improvements" and so help remove a claim from the realm of an abstract idea? Of course, neither the court nor any attorney can provide a specific definition since this would most likely preclude a novel invention. However, the court does suggest certain "technical means" which, based on case law, might have saved the claims, including:</p> <ul> <li> <p>"The claims do not even require a<span style="font-weight: bold;"> new or type of information</span>, or <span style="font-weight: bold;">new technique for analyzing it.</span>"<span style="font-style: italic;"> Id</span> at 9.</p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>The claims "do not require an arguably inventive set of components or methods, such as <span style="font-weight: bold;">measurement devices or techniques</span>, that would <span style="font-weight: bold;">generate new data</span>. <span style="font-style: italic;">Id</span> (emphasis added).</p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>The claims "do not invoke any assertedly <span style="font-weight: bold;">inventive programming</span>." <span style="font-style: italic;">Id</span> (emphasis added).</p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>The claims "do not require any <span style="font-weight: bold;">nonconventional computer, network</span>, or <span style="font-weight: bold;">display components</span>, or even a '<span style="font-weight: bold;">non-conventional and non-generic arrangement of known, conventional pieces.</span>'" <span style="font-style: italic;">Id</span> at 10 (<span style="font-style: italic;">emphasis added</span>).</p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>The claims "do not require an arguably inventive device or technique for displaying information." <span style="font-style: italic;">Id </span>(<span style="font-style: italic;">emphasis added</span>).</p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p>The claims do not "require an arguably inventive <span style="font-weight: bold;">distribution of functionality within a network.</span>" <span style="font-style: italic;">Id </span>(<span style="font-style: italic;">emphasis added</span>).</p> </li> </ul> <p>It would seem from these court-provided samples that a viable "technical means" needs to provide some inventive variation of the computer system on which the method is implemented. Specifically, something beyond implementing the method on an off-the-shelf computer or something beyond the functionality provided by a standard off-the-shelf operating system.&nbsp;</p> <p><a href="/Attorneys/John-C-Laurence.shtml"><img style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" class="mt-image-left" height="112" width="150" src="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/blog/assets_c/2016/09/john laurence-thumb-150x112-75969-thumb-150x112-75945.jpg" alt="Thumbnail image for john laurence.jpg" /></a></p> <p><strong>JOHN LAURENCE</strong></p> <p><strong>212-206-9399</strong></p> <p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.wrsamuelslaw.com/Contact.shtml">Email Me</a></p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>